

Kashif Ismail

Teacher

RESUME OBJECTIVE

Dedicated and accomplished education professional with 21 years of experience in teaching and school administration, seeking a challenging position where I can leverage my expertise to drive continuous improvement and contribute to the academic success of students and the growth of an institution.

Work History

Headmaster A Level/ HSC

The City School, Jinnah Campus Hyderabad, Sindh, 2023 - 2024

- Oversaw teacher development and improvement plans to maximize quality of education offered at school.
- Partnered with senior administration to create cohesive vision, balancing structure and creative expression to drive productive student learning.
- Monitored and evaluated educational programs to maintain highquality performance objectives and standards.

Vice Principal, Indus Campus Sukkur

The City School, Indus Campus, Sukkur, Sindh, 2020 - 2023

- Monitored and evaluated educational programs to maintain highquality performance objectives and standards.
- Encouraged interdepartmental and cross-functional teams collaboration in development and support of student activities, programs and lessons.
- Facilitated continued education for teaching staff through implementation of quality curriculum training and appropriation of necessary resources.
- Monitored student progress and implemented intervention strategies to support student success.
- Administrated school budget and tracked expenses
- Acted as principal for day-to-day running of school as well as key decision making.

Headmaster A Level

Rockford Cambridge School, Hyderabad, Sindh, 2018 – 2020

- Built and lead cohesive educational team focused on student success.
- Oversaw teacher development and improvement plans to maximize quality of education offered at school.
- Monitored and evaluated educational programs to maintain highquality performance objectives and standards.
- Observed teachers, documented activities and implemented improvement plans to optimize classrooms.

CONTACTS

Email:

kashifismail15@yahoo.com

Phone: 03332639349 Address: Hyderabad, SD

71800

SKILLS

Academic

Administration

AcademicIntervention

Faculty Development

Classroom Management

Parental Communication

School Event Coordination

Policy Development and Enforcement

Budget Creation

Educational Staff Supervision

Student Achievement

Process Improvements

EDUCATION

Msc Mathematics: Mathematics

Sindh University, Jamshoro-Hyderabad 1994-09 – 1999-09

HSC II: Pre-Engineering

Government Boys College-Hyderabad 1992 – 08 – 1994 - 09

SSC II: Science

Al Razi school-Hyderabad1982 – 08 – 1992 - 07

Regional Curriculum Lead Science

The City School, Southern Region, Karachi, Sindh 2017 – 2018

- Teamed with subject matter experts in evaluation and revision of training tools in order to continually improve learning platforms.
- Collaborated with colleagues in developing benchmark lessons and identifying curriculum needs of faculty.
- Developed workforce training programs to improve organizational efficiency.
- Planned and monitored implementation of technology-based learning programs.

Headmaster O Level

The City School Indus Campus, Sukkur, Sindh 2014 – 2017

- Maintained operations in compliance with school standards and within limitations of budget guidelines.
- Oversaw teacher development and improvement plans to maximize quality of education offered at school.
- Performed classroom evaluations to assess teacher strategies and effectiveness.

Teacher O / A Level

The City School, Liaquat Campus, Hyderabad, Sindh 2012 – 2014

- Graded and evaluated student assignments, papers and course work.
- Incorporated multiple types of teaching strategies into classrooms.
- Developed and implemented classroom routines to address varying student needs.
- Created and developed lesson plans to meet student's academic needs.

Teacher O / A Level Mathematics

Sarghodian Sprite Trust School, Rashidabad, Hyderabad, Sindh 2010 – 2012

- Graded and evaluated student assignments, papers and course work.
- Incorporated exciting and engaging activities to achieve student participation and hands-on learning
- Incorporated multiple types of teaching strategies into classroom.
- Increased educational expertise and knowledge by participating in instructor-oriented workshops.

Teacher O / A Level

The City School, Hyderabad, Sindh 2005 –2010

- Graded and evaluated student assignments, papers and course work.
- Incorporated multiple types of teaching strategies into classroom.
- Developed and administered tests for students to measure academic proficiency and understanding

Teacher Mathematics / Physics

Royal Cambridge School, Hyderabad, Sindh 2002 - 2005

- Graded and evaluated student assignments, papers and course work.
- Incorporated multiple types of teaching strategies into classroom.